

Serhii Mykhailov

DevOps Engineer

mykhailovsa@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/s-mykhailov t.me/mykhailov s github.com/s-mykhailov mynote.pp.ua fb.com/mykhailov.s/

About me:

Risen from SysAdmin to DevOps.

10+ years of experience as a System Administrator with a huge background in server infrastructure and datacenter operations management, strong knowledge of Windows/Linux, and networking.

3+ years as a DevOps Engineer with experience in Infrastructure as Code (IaC), Configuration as Code (CaC), CI/CD, and proficiency in almost all AWS cloud features.

Results and customer-oriented. Skilled in communication, problem localization and solving, critical thinking, and openmindedness. Self-motivated and self-managing, with a strong ability for self-education. Extremely composed, methodical, and cold-blooded when handling critical issues.

My motto: Anything that needs to be repeated more than twice should be automated.

my work == my hobby.

Experience:

Automat-IT (DevOps company)

Role: DevOps Engineer, Jan 2021 - present

As a DevOps Engineer at Automat-IT, I play an important role in optimizing and streamlining the software development and deployment processes for multiple end customers with various stacks and configurations. Leveraging my expertise in infrastructure automation, CI/CD, and system administration background, I have contributed to enhancing the overall software development lifecycle, infrastructure scalability, fault tolerance, reliability, and scalable software delivery.

Kev Achievements:

- Several migrations from on-prem/Azure MySQL/MSSQL to AWS RDS databases via AWS DMS and 3rd party services
- Developing a Terraform module for the AWS managed OpenSearch service
- Experience with migration of large amounts of data from on-prem VM's to hundreds S3 buckets with continuous replication as part of migration on-prem FTP services to AWS.
- Set up and support both new and existing infrastructure in the cloud across all major cloud providers, with a primary focus on AWS.

Technologies and Tools:

IaC: Terraform, Pulumi, CloudFormation.

CI/CD: Jenkins, GitHub Actions, AWS CodePipeline | CodeBuild.

CaC: Ansible, AWS SSM.

Scripting: Bash, Python, Groovy, SQL.

Monitoring: Cloudwatch, NewRelic, Zabbix, Grafana, Datadog, OpenSearch.

Knowledge of all major AWS tools and services, including EC2, Lambda, ECS, S3, EBS, RDS, ELB, Route53, CloudFront, CloudWatch, and more. Experience with hybrid environments (VMware ESXi + AWS).

LIDER-TREYD LTD (logistics)

Role: System Administrator, 2015 - 2021

Setup and support hypervisors based on Hyper-V; Citrix XEN;

Windows 2008-2016: AD; GPO; DNS; DHCP; IIS; RDP/remote-app; MSSQL; 1C 7-8.2; SEP controller;

Debian based: mysql; apache; owncloud; samba; pbisopen; vsftpd; jabber; motion; docker; zabbix; traccar.

Networking: Mikrotik; Zywall; Draytek; Ubiquiti, HP procurve. Firewall; DHCP; DNS; NAT; openvpn; IPsec; site-to-site VPN; Load-Balancing; WiFi-roaming;

Support users workstations based on Windows XP-10. Selection of components and assembly of bare metal servers. Configuration backups, replications (master-slave), helpdesk services and monitoring. Bash; powershell; python; RouterOS scripting. Cloud providers: DigitalOcean.

Epicall (call centre)

XenServer v6.5 hypervisor. CentOS based VMs. Configuring tunnels for customers servers. Support users workstations based on Ubuntu. Setting up the company's internal LAN and WiFi.

DVBTD (brokerage company)

Role: System Administrator, 2010 - 2014

Debian-based server: LAMP; SAMBA; FTP; OpenVPN; CUPS. Support workstations based on Windows XP-7. Configuring and support company's website, LAN, WiFi.

Education and certification details:

Udemy | AWS SysOps Administrator

2022. AWS SOA-C02 Exam

Certification was successful.

Cert Validation Number: ZXL4JNGCTBB1QH9V.

Udemy | AWS Cloud Practitioner

2021, AWS CLF-C01 exam

Certification was successful.

Cert Validation Number: JV2Z3P2DD1411QS0.

DevOps course Zone3000

2020, DevOps Basics

Successfully completed the course and received a $\,\underline{\text{certificate}}.$

Donetsk National University of Economics and Trade

2010 - 2014, Master

Mechanical engineering

Skills summary:

Operating Systems | Hypervisors | Container runtimes:

Linux: Debian, Alpine, Ubuntu, CenOS, Amazon Linux.

Windows: 7-10, Server 2003-2019

Hyper-V, Proxmox, VMware ESXi, XEN, LXC, Docker

IAAC I CAAC:

Terraform, Pulumi, CloudFormation, Ansible, AWS SSM

CI/CD tools:

Jenkins, CodeBuild/CodePipeline, GitHub Actions

Scripting:

Bash, Python, PowerShell, Groovy, SQL

DB Engines (administration level):

MySQL, MSSQL, RDS Aurora

Hardware:

Mikrotik, Ubiquiti, Zyxel Zywall, Draytek, HP ProCurve, HP proliant, Supermicro. Experience in selecting components and assembling bare-metal servers

Language:

English - Intermediate Ukrainian - Native Russian - Native

Last updated at 13/10/2024 by GitHub Actions